原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
第六季 第九集
权力的游戏
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草 潇湘月影 欧沈娜
■
翻译：盐湖凉开水 ET外星人 妖精希亚
校对：Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
时间轴：aaaBao 加森 Avis
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
陛下
Your Grace.
审判马上就要开始了
The trial will be getting under way soon.
我的钱呢
You got my money?
以后再说  出去
Later. Go away.
大学士
Grand Maester.
洛拉斯·提利尔爵士
Ser Loras Tyrell.
你准备好接受审判
Are you prepared to stand trial
在七神面前陈述陈述你是否有罪吗
and profess your guilt or innocence before the Seven?
没必要审判
There'll be no need for a trial.
我将在七神面前忏悔
I confess before the Seven
自愿供认我的罪行
and freely admit to my crimes.
你要忏悔什么罪
To which crimes will you be confessing?
所有的罪
All of them.
我与男人同寝
I lay with other men
包括反叛蓝礼·拜拉席恩
including the traitor Renly Baratheon.
我在诸神面前作了伪证
I perjured myself before the gods.
我的罪包括堕落
I am guilty of depravity...
不诚实
dishonesty,
放荡
profligacy,
和傲慢
and arrogance.
我已经幡然悔悟
I see that now.
我匍匐在七神面前
I humble myself before the Seven
接受任何诸神认为公正的裁决
and accept whatever punishment the gods deem just.
诸神的裁决激烈
The gods' judgment is fierce,
但也公正
but also fair.
战士惩罚那些自以为
The Warrior punishes those who believe themselves
可以逃脱正义的裁罚之人
beyond the reach of justice.
但圣母则对跪在她面前的人施与慈悲
But the Mother shows her mercy to those who kneel before her.
我为我的诸多罪行承担全部责任
I take full responsibility for my many sins
从此卸下欲念的包袱
and unburden myself of my desires.
我唯一的愿望
My only remaining wish
就是将生命献给七神
is to devote my life to the Seven.
让我成为七神恩典活生生的榜样
May I be a living example of their grace
给其他人见证
for others to witness.
你完全明白
You understand fully
这意味着什么吗
what this means?
我明白
I do.
我将放弃提利尔的姓氏
I will abandon the Tyrell name
以及它代表的一切
and all that goes with it.
我将放弃贵族身份  放弃对高庭的继承权
I will renounce my lordship and my claims on Highgarden.
我将不娶妻
I will never marry
不生子
and I will never father children.
洛拉斯兄弟
Brother Loras...
我请你将生命献给七神
...I ask you to dedicate your life to the seven gods.
你愿意为了信仰与异教徒和叛教者战斗吗
Will you fight to defend your faith against heretics and apostates?
我愿意
I will.
不  我不能让他们...
No, I can't let them--
信仰才是正道  父亲
Faith is the way, Father.
好了
All right.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我必须得去  我...
I have to go. I'm--
出席审批要迟到了
I'm late for the trial.
你羞辱了他
You mutilated him.
你向我保证过的
You gave me your word.
我也信守了承诺
And I have kept my word.
太后的审判一结束
Once the queen mother's trial is concluded,
洛拉斯兄弟就可以离开了
Brother Loras is free to leave.
太后人在哪里
And where is the queen mother?
她根本没有离开红堡
Her litter never left the Red Keep.
看来太后无意出席自己的审判
It appears the queen mother doesn't wish to attend her own trial.
去红堡给她带路
Go to the Red Keep and show her the way.
去叫其他人
Get the others.
国王在哪里
Where's the king?
恐怕不在此处
Elsewhere, I'm afraid.
这是什么意思
What's the meaning of this?
有人告诉我...
I was told that--
我还有更要紧的事情要做
I have more important things to do with my time
没时间跟一个...
than waste them in the presence--
别这样  大学士  我对您没有恶意
Please, Grand Maester. I bear you no ill will.
如果可以  请您原谅我
Please forgive me if you can.
这令我痛苦  大人
This pains me, my lord.
无论你有何等过错  都不至于活该
Whatever your faults, you do not deserve
孤零零地死在这个冰冷黑暗的地方
to die alone in such a cold, dark place.
但有时候为了迎接新主
But sometimes before we can usher in the new,
旧主必须被埋葬
the old must be put to rest.
你躲得越久  结果就越糟
The longer you wait, the worse it'll be for you.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
事情不对头
There's something wrong.
您无需害怕  陛下
You have nothing to fear, Your Grace.
审判马上就开始
The trial will begin shortly.
瑟曦不在这里  托曼也不在
Cersei is not here. Tommen is not here.
你想他们为什么不在
Why do you think they're not here?
如果被告人不出席
If the accused is not here,
我们就做缺席审判
she will be tried regardless.
我们无法逃脱诸神的审判
We cannot escape the justice of the gods--
忘记你该死的诸神  好好听我说
Forget about the bloody gods and listen to what I'm telling you.
瑟曦明白缺席的后果
Cersei understands the consequences of her absence
但她还是缺席
and she is absent anyway,
说明她根本没打算承受这后果
which means she does not intend to suffer those consequences.
审判可以等  我们必须离开
The trial can wait. We all need to leave.
所有人都得马上离开
We all need to leave now.
洛拉斯
Loras.
跟我走
Stay with me.
让我过去  让我过去
Let me through. Let me through.
让开
Get out of my way.
让我们过去
Let us through.
忏悔
Confess.
-不  -忏悔
- No. - Confess.
忏悔吧  那感觉真好
Confess. It felt good.
殴打我  饿着我
Beating me, starving me,
恫吓我  羞辱我
frightening me, humiliating me.
你那样做不是因为你在意我赎罪
You didn't do it because you cared about my atonement.
你那样做是那感觉好
You did it because it felt good.
我理解
I understand.
我也做事也是为了感觉好
I do things because they feel good.
我喝酒  因为那感觉好
I drink because it feels good.
我杀我丈夫  因为摆脱他的感觉很好
I killed my husband because it felt good to be rid of him.
我操我弟弟  因为他在我体内感觉很好
I fuck my brother because it feels good to feel him inside me.
我隐瞒操我弟弟的事
I lie about fucking my brother...
因为保护我们的儿子
because it feels good to keep our son
不受可恶的伪君子伤害感觉很好
safe from hateful hypocrites.
我杀了你的大麻雀
I killed your High Sparrow...
杀光了他的小麻雀
and all his little sparrows...
杀光了他的修士  修女
all his septons, all his septas,
和他肮脏的士兵
all his filthy soldiers,
因为看着他们烧死感觉真好
because it felt good to watch them burn.
因为想象他们的震惊和痛苦感觉真好
It felt good to imagine their shock and their pain.
没有别的想法比这更能让我开心
No thought has ever given me greater joy.
一旦情势对头  连忏悔的感觉都这么好
Even confessing feels good under the right circumstances.
你一直这样沉默
You've always been quiet.
我说过你死前最后看到的会是我的脸
I said my face would be the last thing you saw before you died.
记得吗
Do you remember?
很好
Good.
我很乐意看到你的脸
I'm glad to see your face.
我准备好去见诸神了
I'm ready to meet the gods.
什么
What?
现在
Now?
今天
Today?
你今天不会死的
You're not going to die today.
你好一阵死不了呢
You're not going to die for quite a while.
克里冈爵士
Ser Gregor.
这位是格雷果·克里冈爵士
This is Ser Gregor Clegane.
他也很沉默
He's quiet, too.
你的诸神已经抛弃了你
Your gods have forsaken you.
他就是你的神了
This is your god now.
不
No.
耻辱
Shame.
我很遗憾  陛下
I'm very sorry, Your Grace.
很遗憾
Very sorry.
敬兰尼斯特家族
For House Lannister!
听我怒吼
Hear me roar!
敬佛雷家族
For House Frey!
并肩作战
We stand together!
愿我们能一直并肩作战
May we stand together through the centuries,
永为好友
good friends to the last.
我们用剑刺穿敌人心脏时
And when we drive our swords through our enemies' hearts,
愿我们说出结盟的话语
may we speak the words of our alliance,
"佛雷家和兰尼斯特家
"The Freys and the Lannisters
向你致意"
send their regards."
你什么都不用做  是吧
You don't even have to do anything, do you?
你只消往那一坐  好一块鲜肉
You just sit there, a rich slab of beef,
所有鸟儿都想啄一口
and all the birds come pecking.
-她可以让给你  -她不想要我
- You're welcome to her. - She doesn't want me.
她要你的金手指插她的屄
She wants your golden fingers up her twat.
那俩就看好你了
Those two have their eyes on you.
她们是看好你了  混蛋
They have their eyes on you, cunt.
不合我胃口
Not my type.
头发不够金吗
Not blonde enough?
女士们  这位是黑水的波隆爵士
Ladies, have you met Ser Bronn of the Blackwater,
黑水湾大战的英雄
hero of the Battle of Blackwater Bay?
-上吧  -或许我没心情呢
- There you go. - Maybe I'm not in the mood.
去他的
Fuck it.
不要因为我是抹过圣油的骑士就叫咱爵士
No need to call me ser just because I'm an anointed knight.
结果还不错嘛
This came together rather well.
你父亲在天有灵会高兴的
Your father would be pleased.
肯定的
I'm sure he would be.
艾德慕又关回牢里了
Edmure is back in a cell.
不能杀自家女婿哟  那可不成
Can't go killing my son by law. It wouldn't be right.
会败坏家族名声的
Give the family a bad name.
威名赫赫的黑鱼死在小卒手里  是吗
So the famous Blackfish killed by foot soldiers, eh?
人人都说他是传奇的战士
Legendary warrior, everyone said.
你自己打过仗吗  佛雷大人
Have you done much fighting yourself, Lord Frey?
我这把年纪打不动了
I'm a bit old for all that.
是啊  但当年呢
No, but back in your day.
战斗的目的
The purpose of fighting
在于击败敌人  不是吗
is defeating your enemies, isn't it?
我击败了我的敌人
I've defeated mine.
奔流城在徒利家族手里千年
Riverrun belonged to House Tully for a thousand years.
如今归我了
Now it's mine.
这叫什么
What do you call that?
胜利
Victory.
是啊  你真是个伟大的征服者
Yes, you're a great conqueror.
尽管嘲笑我  小子  你以为我会在意吗
Go on, mock me, boy. You think I mind?
徒利家嘲笑了我好多年
The Tullys mocked me for years.
史塔克家也嘲笑我
The Starks mocked me.
他们如今在哪里
Where are they now?
你像个行家似的跟我谈论战争
You talk about war as if you're an expert,
但我能记得的  你打过的那场仗
but the one battle I remember you fighting,
你给少狼主罗柏·史塔克抓了俘虏
you were captured by Robb Stark, the Young Wolf.
不过没关系
But it doesn't matter.
瞧瞧我们  两个弑君者
Here we are now, two kingslayers.
我们都知道被人当面阿谀奉承
We know what it's like to have them grovel to our faces
背地里被嘲笑的滋味
and snigger behind our backs.
我们不在乎  是不是
We don't mind, do we?
恐惧是了不起的东西
Fear is a marvelous thing.
但他们怕的不是佛雷
They don't fear the Freys, though.
他们怕的是兰尼斯特
They fear the Lannisters.
我们把河间地交给你们  是让你们守住的
We gave you the Riverlands to hold the Riverlands.
如果每次你们守不住  都要我们挥师北上
If we have to ride north and take them back for you
才能夺回来
every time you lose them,
那还要你们何用
why do we need you?
让我看看
Show me.
陛下  没必要...
Your Grace, there's no need--
让我看看
Show me.
您认为国王的葬礼该怎么办
What are your thoughts concerning the king's funeral?
贝勒大圣堂已经没法举行葬礼
As the Sept of Baelor is no longer an option,
也许可以在王座厅办
perhaps a ceremony in the throne room?
他该跟他外祖父
He should be with his grandfather,
他的哥哥和姐姐在一起
his brother, his sister.
将他火化
Burn him
骨灰埋在大圣堂遗址
and bury his ashes where the sept once stood.
你好
Hello.
这是黑城堡雪诺总司令的信
From Lord Commander Snow at Castle Black.
我...
I'm--
我来成为新学士
I'm to be the new maester.
根据我们的记录
According to our records,
杰奥·莫尔蒙才是总司令
Jeor Mormont is Lord Commander.
他去世了
He died.
我们没有接到黑城堡的学士的报告
We received no report from the maester at Castle Black.
伊蒙学士在推选新司令后不久就病重
Maester Aemon became quite ill shortly after the election.
然后去世了
He's since passed away.
所以我才会来
Which is why I'm here.
这不合规矩
This is irregular.
是的  我想生活本就无规可循
Yes, well, I suppose that life is irregular.
博士们会跟你讨论这些非常规情况
The archmaester will discuss these irregularities with you.
在此期间  你可以使用图书馆
In the meantime, you are permitted to use the library.
跟我来
Follow me.
女人孩子不得入内
No women or children.
宴会上
When we had feasts,
我家里人都坐在这里
our family would sit up here...
而我坐在下面那边
and I'd sit down there.
这不算太糟  琼恩·雪诺
Could have been worse, Jon Snow.
你至少有过家人
You had a family.
参加过宴会
You had feasts.
是啊  你说得对  我比大多数人都要幸运
Aye, you're right. I was luckier than most.
那是什么
What is that?
告诉他
Tell him.
告诉他那东西是谁的
Tell him who it belonged to.
希琳公主
The Princess Shireen.
告诉他你对她做了什么
Tell him what you did to her.
告诉他
Tell him!
我们烧死了她
We burned her at the stake.
为什么
Why?
大军被困  马匹不断死亡
The army was trapped. The horses were dying.
-这是唯一的办法  -你活活烧死了一个小女孩
- It was the only way. - You burned a little girl alive!
我只是听从光之王的旨意
I only do what my Lord commands.
命令你烧死孩子  你的光之王就是邪神
If he commands you to burn children, your Lord is evil.
我们能站在这里多亏了祂
We are standing here because of him.
琼恩·雪诺复活也是光之王的意志
Jon Snow is alive because the Lord willed it.
我爱那小姑娘  把她当作自己的女儿
I loved that girl like she was my own.
她那么好  那么善良  你却杀了她
She was good. She was kind. And you killed her!
她父亲也有份
So did her father.
她母亲也有份
So did her mother.
她的血亲也明白这是唯一的办法
Her own blood knew it was the only way.
什么唯一的办法
The only way for what?
反正他们还是死了
They all died anyway.
你告诉所有人史坦尼斯是唯一的真王
You told everyone Stannis was the one.
你让他深信不疑  你蒙骗了所有人
You had him believing it, all of them fooled.
-你还说谎  -我没有说谎
- And you lied. - I didn't lie.
我犯了错
I was wrong.
是啊  你犯了错
Aye, you were wrong.
多少人因你的错误而死
How many died because you were wrong?
我请你允许我以谋杀罪处死这个女人
I ask your leave to execute this woman for murder.
她已经认罪了
She admits to the crime.
你还有什么要辩解的吗
Do you have anything to say for yourself?
我许多年前就准备好赴死了
I've been ready to die for many years.
如果光之王给我的使命已经完成
If the Lord was done with me,
那我认命  但还没有
so be it, but he's not.
你看见过夜王  琼恩·雪诺
You've seen the Night King, Jon Snow.
你知道大战还在后面
You know the great war is still to come.
你知道死人军团正在迫近
You know the army of the dead will be upon us soon.
你知道我可以帮你打赢这场战争
And you know I can help you win that war.
你今天就启程南下
Ride south today.
如果再回到北境
If you return to the North,
我会以谋杀罪绞死你
I'll have you hanged as a murderer.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
如果你胆敢回来
If you ever come back this way,
我会亲手处死你
I will execute you myself.
我叫了人给你收拾领主卧室
I'm having the lord's chamber prepared for you.
父亲母亲的房间吗
Mother and Father's room?
应该你去住
You should take it.
我不是史塔克
I'm not a Stark.
对我来说  你就是
You are to me.
你是临冬城夫人
You're the Lady of Winterfell.
这是你应得的  我们此刻能站在这里全靠你
You deserve it. We're standing here because of you.
艾林谷的骑兵到来之前  我们必败无疑
The battle was lost until the Knights of the Vale rode in.
他们因你而来
They came because of you.
你说贝里席大人把你卖给了波顿家
You told me Lord Baelish sold you to the Boltons.
-的确如此  -那你还相信他
- He did. - And you trust him?
只有傻瓜才会相信小指头
Only a fool would trust Littlefinger.
我本该早些告诉你的
I should have told you about him,
告诉你艾林谷的骑兵的事
about the Knights of the Vale.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们应该相信彼此
We need to trust each other.
我们不能起内讧
We can't fight a war amongst ourselves.
我们的敌人已经太多
We have so many enemies now.
琼恩
Jon.
学城有信鸦来
A raven came from the Citadel.
是白鸦
A white raven.
凛冬已至
Winter is here.
父亲就说凛冬将至  不是吗
Well, Father always promised, didn't he?
上次有提利尔家的人来多恩
The last time a Tyrell came to Dorne,
他遇刺身亡
he was assassinated.
一百只红蝎  是吧
100 red scorpions, was it?
你无需惧怕我们  奥莲娜夫人
You have nothing to fear from us, Lady Olenna.
你谋杀了自己的亲王
You murder your own prince,
还指望我相信你
but you expect me to trust you?
我们邀请你前来多恩  是需要你帮忙
We invited you to Dorne because we needed your help.
而你赴约是因为需要我们帮忙
You came to Dorne because you needed our help.
你叫什么名字来着
What is your name again?
芭芭娅
Barbaro?
奥芭娅
Obara.
奥芭娅  你就像个耍脾气的小小子
Obara. You look like an angry little boy.
别乱猜我需要什么
Don't presume to tell me what I need.
请原谅我妹妹  她不懂什么外交  但...
Forgive my sister. What she lacks in diplomacy, she makes--
闭嘴吧  亲爱的  你也有话要说吗
Do shut up, dear. Anything from you?
没有  很好
No? Good.
让成熟女性对话
Let the grown women speak.
兰尼斯特家族向提利尔家族宣战
The Lannisters have declared war on House Tyrell.
也向多恩宣战
They have declared war on Dorne.
想要生存  我们必须结盟
We must be allies now if we wish to survive.
瑟曦毁了我的未来
Cersei stole the future from me.
她杀了我儿子
She killed my son.
杀了我孙儿
She killed my grandson.
杀了我孙女
She killed my granddaughter.
我现在要的不是生存
Survival is not what I'm after now.
你说得对
You're absolutely right.
我措辞有问题
I chose the wrong words.
我能给你的不是生存
It is not survival I offer.
我可以给你你最最想要的
It is your heart's desire.
我最最想要的是什么
And what is my heart's desire?
复仇
Vengeance.
正义
Justice.
血与火
Fire and blood.
你的船队就要准备好了
Your ships are nearly ready.
我看到他们在绘制船帆
I saw them painting the sails.
真想知道多斯拉克人在毒水上是什么样子
I'm curious to see how the Dothraki do on the poison water.
你不随我们一起走
You're not coming with us.
新战术吗
New strategy?
你想要次子团从西海岸进攻
You want the Second Sons to attack from the west coast?
如果我们拿下凯岩城
If we take Casterly Rock,
当你进攻君临
the Lannisters will have nowhere to run
兰尼斯特家族将无处可逃
when you hit King's Landing.
你不去维斯特洛
You're not going to Westeros.
你将带领次子团驻留此处
You're staying here with the Second Sons.
弥林终于迎来了和平
There's finally peace in Meereen.
你将在人民选举领袖期间维护和平
You will keep the peace while the people choose their own leaders.
去他的弥林
Fuck Meereen.
去他的人民
Fuck the people.
我是为你而来  不是为他们
I'm here for you, not them.
你曾向我发誓
You promised me.
"我的剑属于您  我的命属于您"
"My sword is yours. My life is yours."
这就是我的命令
This is what I command.
我如果要统治维斯特洛
If I'm going to rule in Westeros,
就得与人结盟
I'll need to make alliances.
而结盟的最佳方式就是联姻
The best way to make alliances is with marriage.
这回你要跟谁结婚
Who are you marrying this time?
我不知道  或许不结婚
I don't know. Maybe no one.
但你真的需要引诱所有贵族吗
But you need to lure all the noble houses to the table?
你到底是女王还是鱼饵
Are you a queen or fish bait?
我不能带着个情人去维斯特洛
I can't bring a lover to Westeros.
一个国王就完全不会犹豫这种事
A king wouldn't think twice about it.
难道这就是你想要的  做我的情人
So that's what you want? To be my mistress?
我并不以此为荣  我也不在乎哪个喷香水的贵族
I'm not proud. I don't care what perfumed aristocrat
在王座厅里坐在你身旁
sits beside you in the throne room.
我不要王冠  我只要你
I don't want a crown. I want you.
我爱你
I love you.
我想让你快乐
And I make you happy.
你知道的
You know I do.
带上我吧  让我为你而战
Bring me with you. Let me fight for you.
我做不到
I can't.
是侏儒让你这样做的吗
The dwarf told you to do this?
没人让我做任何事
No one tells me to do anything.
他是个聪明的家伙  道理我讲不过他
Clever fellow. Can't argue with his logic.
到那边我就没什么用处了
I'm no use to you over there.
不要生气
Don't get angry.
我没生气  我是在自怨自艾
I'm not angry. I'm full of self-pity.
没了你我去找谁
Who comes after you?
哪里有人比得上风暴降生丹妮莉丝  龙之母
Who can ever follow Daenerys Stormborn, the Mother of Dragons?
我想会有很多女人的
A great number of women, I imagine.
我将给你下达具体的命令
Specific orders will be left for you
来确保弥林和龙之湾的安定
regarding the welfare of Meereen and the Bay of Dragons.
龙之湾
Bay of Dragons?
总不能还叫奴隶湾  是不是
We can't call it Slaver's Bay anymore, can we?
你会得到梦寐以求的王座  我确定
You'll get that throne you want so badly, I'm sure of it.
希望它能让你快乐
I hope it brings you happiness.
我可怜维斯特洛的老爷们
I pity the lords of Westeros.
他们根本想不到将要面临什么
They have no idea what's coming for them.
再会  达里奥·纳哈里斯
Farewell, Daario Naharis.
他反应如何
How did he take it?
没哭
No tears.
我知道这对您不容易
I know it was hard for you.
拒绝了一个深爱着您的男人
You turned away a man who truly loves you
因为他在七国会成为不利因素
because he would have been a liability in the Seven Kingdoms.
一个伟大的统治者需要做出如此的自我牺牲
That's the kind of self-sacrifice that makes for a good ruler,
如果这样讲能提供些安慰
if it's any consolation.
不能
It's not.
是啊  我想也没用
No, I suppose not.
我特别不擅长安慰人
I'm terrible at consoling.
的确如此
Yes, you really are.
那就想想这一天终于来了
All right, how about the fact that this is actually happening?
您有军队  有船
You have your armies, you have your ships,
还有龙
you have your dragons.
从您曾经想要的一切
Everything you've ever wanted
从儿时就向往的一切
since you were old enough to want anything,
已经唾手可得
it's all yours for the taking.
您害怕吗
Are you afraid?
很好
Good.
您已身处局中
You're in the great game now.
此局凶险骇人
And the great game's terrifying.
只有您父亲那样的疯子
The only people who aren't afraid of failure
才不害怕失败
are madmen like your father.
你知道是什么让我害怕吗
Do you know what frightens me?
我与一个爱我的男人道别
I said farewell to a man who loves me.
一个我以为我真心在乎的人
A man I thought I cared for.
而我的内心毫无感觉
And I felt nothing.
只有尽快结束的不耐烦
Just impatient to get on with it.
他不是第一个爱您的人
He wasn't the first to love you
也不会是最后一个
and he won't be the last.
你对我的安慰完全失败了
Well, you have completely failed to console me.
说起来  从记事起我就是个玩世不恭的人
For what it's worth, I've been a cynic for as long as I can remember.
所有人都要我信这信那
Everyone's always asking me to believe in things--
信家族  信诸神  信国王  相信自己
family, gods, kings, myself.
信仰还是有吸引力的
It was often tempting
直到我看到人们是怎样被信仰所捉弄
until I saw where belief got people.
所以我说  不  我拒绝信仰
So I said no, thank you to belief.
然而现在
And yet here I am.
我相您
I believe in you.
有点尴尬
It's embarrassing, really.
我想以剑之名对您发誓
I'd swear you my sword,
可我其实也没有剑
but I don't actually own a sword.
我需要的是你的辅佐
It's your counsel I need.
我将辅佐您
It's yours.
直到永远
Now and always.
很好
Good.
我
I, um...
我叫人给你做了件东西
I had something made for you.
不确定做得对不对
I'm not sure if it's right.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
Tyrion Lannister,
我任命你为女王之手
I name you Hand of the Queen.
你不是我的吧
You're not one of mine, are you?
不是  大人
No, my lord.
我想也不是
Didn't think so.
太漂亮
Too pretty.
我的蠢儿子们在哪里
Where are my damn moron sons?
黑瓦德和罗索答应了会在中午前到这里
Black Walder and Lothar promised to be here by midday.
他们就在这  大人
They're here, my lord.
他们在干什么  理屌毛吗
Well, what are they doing, trimming their cunt hairs?
叫他们现在过来
Tell them to come here now.
但他们已经在这了  大人
But they're already here, my lord.
在这  大人
Here, my lord.
他们可不好切
They weren't easy to carve.
尤其是黑瓦德
Especially Black Walder.
什么...
What...
我的名字叫艾莉亚·史塔克
My name is Arya Stark.
我要你知道
I want you to know that.
你在世上看到的最后一幕
The last thing you're ever going to see
是一个史塔克笑着看你死去
is a Stark smiling down at you as you die.
恕我打扰  小姐...
Forgive me, my lady...
如果你在祈祷
if you're at prayer.
我早就不祈祷了
I'm done with all that.
小时候我天天来这
I came here every day when I was a girl.
祈祷着能去其他地方
I prayed to be somewhere else.
那时候我只会想自己想要什么
Back then I only thought about what I wanted,
从不想自己拥有什么
never about what I had.
我是个愚蠢的姑娘
I was a stupid girl.
那时你还是个孩子
You were a child.
你要什么
What do you want?
我以为你知道我想要什么
I thought you knew what I wanted.
我想错了
I was wrong.
不  你没有
No, you weren't.
每次面临抉择
Every time I'm faced with a decision,
我闭上双眼就会看到同一个画面
I close my eyes and see the same picture.
每次考虑要怎么做时  我就问自己
Whenever I consider an action, I ask myself
这能帮我实现这个画面吗
will this action help to make this picture a reality?
把脑海中想象的画面
Pull it out of my mind
变成现实
and into the world?
我只会在肯定答案下采取行动
And I only act if the answer is yes.
那个画面便是我坐上铁王座
A picture of me on the Iron Throne...
而你在我身边
and you by my side.
画面很美
It's a pretty picture.
这次战役的消息很快就会传遍七大王国
News of this battle will spread quickly through the Seven Kingdoms.
我已宣告要效忠于史塔克家族
I've declared for House Stark for all to hear.
你也曾效忠于其他家族  贝里席大人
You've declared for other houses before, Lord Baelish.
结果还不是为了效忠自己
It's never stopped you from serving yourself.
过去的已经过去了
The past is gone for good.
你可以选择坐在这里哀悼过往
You can sit here mourning its departure
你也可以整装待发
or you can prepare for the future.
你  亲爱的
You, my love,
是史塔克家族的未来
are the future of House Stark.
谁才应该是北境拥护的人
Who should the North rally behind?
是生在临冬城
A trueborn daughter of Ned and Catelyn Stark
奈德和凯特琳·史塔克的正统女儿
born here at Winterfell
还是在南边出生的没妈的私生子
or a motherless bastard born in the south?
我就送你们到这里
This is where I leave you.
你不跟我们一起走吗
You're not coming with us?
长城不只是由冰和石头组成
The Wall is not just ice and stone.
它的根基刻有古老的咒语
Ancient spells were carved into its foundations.
保护人类免受墙外侵扰的强大魔法
Strong magic to protect men from what lies beyond.
只要它屹立不倒  死人就无法入境
And while it stands, the dead cannot pass.
我也无法入境
I cannot pass.
你要去哪里
Where will you go?
大战即将来临
The great war is coming
我仍为生者而战
and I still fight for the living.
我会竭尽全力...
I'll do what I can...
直到最后
as long as I can.
谢谢你  班扬叔叔
Thank you, Uncle Benjen.
祝你们好运
I wish you both good fortune.
你确定自己准备好了吗
Are you sure you're ready for this?
我现在是三眼乌鸦了
I'm the Three-Eyed Raven now.
我必须准备好
I have to be ready for this.
奈德
Ned?
莱安娜
Lyanna.
是你吗
Is that you?
真是你吗
Is that really you?
我不是在做梦吗
You're not a dream?
不  这不是梦
No, I'm not a dream.
我来了
I'm here.
就在这
Right here.
我很想你  哥哥
I've missed you, big brother.
我也想你
I've missed you, too.
我想要勇敢起来
I want to be brave.
你很勇敢
You are.
我不勇敢
I'm not.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
你不会死的
You're not going to die.
拿点水来
Get her some water.
-不  不要水  -有学士吗
- No, no water. - Is there a maester?
听我说  奈德
Listen to me, Ned.
如果劳勃发现了  他会...
If Robert finds out, he'll--
你知道他会的
you know he will.
你一定要保护他
You have to protect him.
答应我  奈德
Promise me, Ned.
答应我
Promise me.
答应我  奈德
Promise me, Ned.
答应我
Promise me.
别指望谷地骑士
You can't expect Knights of the Vale
会跟野人侵略者并肩作战
to side with wildling invaders.
我们没有侵略  我们是受邀而来
We didn't invade. We were invited.
不是受我之邀
Not by me.
自由民  北方人
The free folk, the northerners,
以及谷地骑士英勇战斗
and the Knights of the Vale fought bravely,
并肩作战  赢得了胜利
fought together, and we won.
我父亲曾说
My father used to say
战场见真交
we find our true friends on the battlefield.
波顿家族已经覆败
The Boltons are defeated.
战争结束了
The war is over.
凛冬已至
Winter has come.
如果学士说得没错
If the maesters are right,
这将是一千年来最冷的冬天
it'll be the coldest one in a thousand years.
我们应该赶紧回家  等待暴风雪过去
We should ride home and wait out the coming storms.
战争没有结束
The war is not over.
我向你们保证  朋友
And I promise you, friend,
真正的敌人不会等暴风雪过去
the true enemy won't wait out the storm.
他会带来暴风雪
He brings the storm.
你的儿子在红色婚礼上遇害  曼德勒大人
Your son was butchered at the Red Wedding, Lord Manderly,
而你拒不奉召
but you refused the call.
你曾宣誓效忠史塔克家族  葛洛佛大人
You swore allegiance to House Stark, Lord Glover,
但在他们最需要帮助的时刻
but in their hour of greatest need,
你拒不奉召
you refused the call.
还有你  赛文大人
And you, Lord Cerwyn,
你父亲被拉姆斯·波顿活剥
your father was skinned alive by Ramsay Bolton.
而你仍然拒不奉召
Still you refused the call.
但莫尔蒙家族永不遗忘
But House Mormont remembers.
北境永不遗忘
The North remembers.
我们不承认除北境之王外的任何君主
We know no king but the King in the North
而北境之王出自史塔克
whose name is Stark.
我不在乎他是不是私生子
I don't care if he's a bastard.
奈德·史塔克的血液在他体内流淌
Ned Stark's blood runs through his veins.
他就是我的君主  自今日起  至死方休
He's my king from this day until his last day.
莫尔蒙小姐言辞犀利
Lady Mormont speaks harshly
亦是真知灼见
and truly.
我的儿子为少狼主罗柏·史塔克而死
My son died for Robb Stark, the Young Wolf.
我本想此生不再效忠任何君主
I didn't think we'd find another king in my lifetime.
我没有把手下交给你们
I didn't commit my men to your cause
是因为我不希望曼德勒家族再做无谓的牺牲
'cause I didn't want more Manderlys dying for nothing.
但是我错了
But I was wrong.
琼恩·雪诺已报了红色婚礼之仇
Jon Snow avenged the Red Wedding.
他是白狼主
He is the White Wolf.
北境之王
The King in the North.
我不曾与你并肩作战
I did not fight beside you on the field
为此我将悔恨终生
and I will regret that until my dying day.
只有勇于承认错误之人
A man can only admit when he was wrong
才能请求宽恕
and ask forgiveness.
无需宽恕  大人
There's nothing to forgive, my lord.
未来将有更多战争
There will be more fights to come.
葛洛佛家族将站在史塔克家族身后
House Glover will stand behind House Stark
一千年来一如既往
as we have for a thousand years.
而我将站在琼恩·雪诺身后
And I will stand behind Jon Snow...
北境之王
the King in the North!
The King in the North!
北境之王  北境之王
The King in the North! The King in the North!
停止前进
Company halt!
停
Halt!
快走
Come on.
我在此宣告兰尼斯特家族的
I now proclaim Cersei of the House Lannister
瑟曦一世
First of Her Name,
安达尔人和先民的女王
Queen of the Andals and the First Men,
七国守护
Protector of the Seven Kingdoms.
愿她统治长久
Long may she reign.
■
人人影视字幕组
官方APP
更新下载手机搞定
讨论交流登陆升级
到各大市场搜索
"人人影视字幕组"
下载网址：app.zimuzu.tv
■